selfridges.com 2019-07-16

# Privacy & cookie policy | Our corporate policies |

#### **Introduction**  

Selfridges is committed to protecting your personal information. It’s your information, and we respect that. Our Privacy Policy gives you detailed information on when and why we collect your personal information, how we use it and how we keep it secure. This Privacy Policy also sets out your right to request that we delete, update, transfer or provide you with access to your personal information. This Privacy Policy should be read alongside our  _Terms& Conditions._ Please also note that this Privacy Policy only applies to personal information obtained by us – not information collected from your interactions with third parties.  

#### **Who we are and how to contact us**  

The Sites (Stores, Website and App), and our Services (e.g. Personal Shopping, Alterations, Safe Deposit Boxes etc.) are operated by Selfridges Retail Limited.  

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or want to exercise your rights set out in this Privacy Policy, please e-mail our Data Protection Officer at [dataprotectionofficer@selfridges.co.uk](mailto:dataprotectionofficer@selfridges.co.uk)  

#### **How we collect your personal information**

Generally, we collect your information when you decide to interact with us. This could include purchasing online, over the phone, in person when you sign up to receive emails from us. We also look at how customers use our website, so that we can offer the best possible experience.   

#### **The types of information we collect**

We only collect the information that’s necessary to carry out our business, provide the particular service you’ve requested and to keep you up to date about all the latest exciting Selfridges news.      

#### **Ensuring your personal information is only used where lawful**

In order for our use of your personal information to comply with applicable data protection law, that use by us needs to fall under at least one of the specific lawful reasons that are set out in applicable data protection law. Examples of these lawful reasons include our use of your personal information being necessary for the purchase of goods or services, or for compliance with a legal obligation.      

#### **Why we collect your personal information and how we use it**

At Selfridges we like to get to know our customers – after all, this is how we find new ways to provide you with an extraordinary experience. We use information about you in a number of ways, including providing the services that you have requested, offering you a personalised experience and informing you about special events or exciting Selfridges news. We might also use the information we have to contact you about any information we might need to process your orders, returns or queries.    

#### **The Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (PECR)**

Where we have collected your contact details in the process of a sale (or negotiations of a sale) either in store or online, of a product or service, Selfridges will have PECR compliant permission to send you email marketings. We will only send you emails to market  Selfridge’s products and services.

You will be able to say no to receive these emails when we first collect your contact details and you will be able to unsubscribe in every subsequent communication from us.

#### **Sharing your information**

We use third party platforms to manage and deliver customer relationship management (CRM); email marketing campaigns; online advertising, customer analytics, events; booking of appointments, fulfillment of orders, delivery, returns, refunds, IT services; etc. In providing the services, your personal information will, where applicable, be used by the service provider on our behalf.

We will check any third party that we use to ensure that they can provide sufficient guarantees regarding the confidentiality and security of your personal information. We will have written contracts with them which provide assurances regarding the protections that they will give to your personal information and their compliance with our data security standards and international transfer restrictions.

#### **Business Administration and Legal Compliance**

In certain circumstances, we share and/or are obliged to share your personal information for business administration and legal compliance purposes with third parties outside the Selfridges Group.  

#### **How can I unsubscribe from marketing communications?  **     

We would be sad to say goodbye, but if at any point you do not wish to hear from us there are a number of ways you can unsubscribe.  

#### **Our use of cookies and similar technologies  **     

Our website, app and emails contain certain cookies, pixels, records and other technologies of which you should be aware.  

#### **Third Party Links and services     **  

Our website, app and emails contain links to third party websites and services. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Sites to another website or you request a service from a third party, this Privacy Policy no longer applies.  

#### **Children**

Customers need to be over 16 years old to create an account with us and to sign up to receive our newsletter. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of sixteen (16). If you are under the age of sixteen (16), please do not submit any Personal Data through the Services. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children never to provide Personal Data through the Sites and Services without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 16 has provided Personal Data to us through the Services, please email our Data Protection Officer at [dataprotectionofficer@selfridges.co.uk](mailto:dataprotectionofficer@selfridges.co.uk) and we will endeavour to delete that information from our databases.

Please note that customers need to be at least 18 years old to open (or be granted access to) a Safe Deposit box.

#### **How long do we keep your personal information for?**  

We keep your personal information in line with our company retention policy and as required to comply with any legislation. We only retain information for as long as it is required.  

#### **Confidentiality and security of your personal information**  

We are committed to keeping the personal information you provide to us secure and we will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. We do not sell your personal information for any purpose.  

#### **How to access your information and your other rights**  

You have the following rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you:      

#### **Changes to this Privacy Policy**  

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time.  

#### **Introduction**

We use cookies and similar technologies (“ **Cookies** ”) on www.Selfridges.com and the Selfridges mobile application (the “ **Sites** ”) for identification, analysis and advertising purposes. By using our Sites you consent to the storing and accessing of Cookies on your device.

This cookie policy (“ **Cookie Policy** “) is intended to inform you how we use Cookies to assist you in making informed decisions when using the Sites. Please take a moment to read and understand this Cookie Policy. This Cookie Policy should also be read in conjunction with our _Privacy Policy_ and our _Terms and Conditions_ **.**

Cookies are very small text documents or pieces of software code, which often include an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website or use a mobile application, a computer asks your PC or mobile device for permission to store this file on your computer or mobile device and access information from it. Information gathered through Cookies include the date and time of visits and how you are using the website or mobile application.

Cookies are used by us and our third party partners as part of our Sites. Details of the Cookies used on our Sites and any applicable third party partner are set out in the table below.

For more details on Cookies please visit [_All about Cookies_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Our use of cookies generally requires your consent**  

When you first access our Sites you will be asked to consent to our use of the Cookies described in this Cookie Policy.

Our Sites also uses Cookies for which we do not require your consent. This Cookie Policy refers to these Cookies as “Strictly Necessary Cookies” and without them the services that you have asked for cannot be provided.

**Blocking cookies**  

You can consent to, or block the use of, specific Cookies by activating the relevant settings in your browser or by following the links below.

For more information on Cookie management and blocking Cookies for a wide variety of browsers, please visit [_All about Cookies_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**What happens when you do not consent to cookies and or you choose to block cookies that you have previously accepted?**

In order to use some parts of our Sites you will need to consent to Cookies. If you choose to withhold consent, or subsequently block cookies, some aspects of our Sites may not work properly and you may not be able to access all or part of Sites.

**What cookies do we use?**

The list below sets out more information about the individual Cookies used on our Sites and the purposes for which they are used:

#### **[_Google Analytics_](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)  _utma  _utmz**

  * These cookies help us make the most of the money we spend on advertising. Google Analytics uses these cookies to discover when you first visited our site, how often you come back and how long you spend shopping. The information stored by these cookies can be seen only by the relevant teams at Selfridges and Google and never shows any confidential information.      
Type: Analytics

#### **[_DC Storm_](https://dc-storm.com/en-uk/cookie-use/), [ _Affiliate Window_](https://www.awin.com/gb/legal/privacy-policy),  [_Skimlinks_](https://skimlinks.com/user-cookies), [ _Facebook_](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/), [ _Pinterest_](https://policy.pinterest.com/en-gb/cookies) and  _[Google](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies)/[Double Click](https://support.google.com/dfp_premium/answer/2839090?hl=en)_**

  * Sometimes we'll advertise on third party websites and these tags are used to help us and our advertisers see which advertisements you click on and interact with. Each individual advertiser uses its own tracking cookies and the data taken is not confidential or interchangeable.  
Type: Advertising  

We know you love to share the great content we have on selfridges.com. Please be aware that social networking sites, like Facebook and Twitter, might send cookies. We don't control the setting of these third-party cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them. 

## C. selfridges.com 'share' tools  

We know you love to share the great content we have on selfridges.com. Please be aware that social networking sites, like Facebook and Twitter, might send cookies. We don't control the setting of these third-party cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them. The business partners that may set cookies on selfridges.com include:  

  *  

#### **DC Storm, Affiliate Window and Google**

  * Sometimes we'll advertise on third party websites and DC Storm cookies are used to help us and our advertisers see which advertisements you click on and interact with. Each individual advertiser uses its own tracking cookies and the data taken is not confidential or interchangeable.

We hope that explains things clearly – and please be aware you can set your browser to reject cookies or you can delete them yourself if you wish. For full information on how to delete cookies please visit aboutcookies.org (this will open in a new window – please note that we can't be responsible for the content of external websites).

Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy and cookies policy.

For any questions regarding this policy, please contact us using our _online form._
